Guide to the Eric Moe Collection, 1976- UA.90.F96
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Fancy Footwork, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  Instruments: [Oboe and piano]
  Dedication: [for Marcia Butler]
  Note: Appears in published score "Sad Steps and Fancy Footwork"
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 8 leaves (2 blank)., 1.
  - Computer-generated draft with pencil corrections. Printed on both sides, sometimes unclear if both sides are for this piece or if one is reused scratch paper. 62 pages., 2.
  - Notes on sound recording. Pencil and photocopy. 8 pages., 3.
- Kicking and Screaming, 1994 (Box 12, Folder ?)
  Instrumentation: Piano, Flute, Oboe/English Horn, Clarinet/Bass Clarinet, Bassoon, Horn, Violin I, Violin II, Viola, Violoncello, Percussion.
  Dedication: for Aleck Karis.
  Commissioned by: The Fromm Foundation.
  At end: "7/94 MacDowell Colony"
  - Box labeled "K & S Master, drafts other scores", 1.
    a. Errata sheet. Handwritten. 2 pages. b. Set-up diagram. Handwritten. 1 page. c. Full score. Computer-generated drafts, Movement 3. d. Full score. Computer-generated drafts with pencil corrections. On some pages, one side appears to be "Kicking and Screaming," but it is not clear what piece is on the other side.
  - Errata sheet. Handwritten. In envelope with individual parts for each instrument., 1. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Flute part. Computer-generated score., 2.
  - Oboe part. Computer-generated score., 3.
  - Clarinet/Bass Clarinet part. Computer-generated score., 4.
  - Bassoon part. Computer-generated score., 5.
  - Horn part. Computer-generated score., 6.
  - Violin I part. Computer-generated score., 7.
  - Violin II part. Computer-generated score., 8.
  - Viola part. Computer-generated score., 9.
  - Violoncello part. Computer-generated score., 10.
  - Percussion part. Computer-generated score., 11.
  - Sketches., 12.
  - Full score. Autograph manuscript and computer-generated drafts and revised pages. In envelope., 1. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Flute part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 1. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Oboe part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 2.
  - Clarinet/Bass Clarinet part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 3.
  - Bassoon part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 4.
  - Horn part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 5.
  - Violin I part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 6.
  - Violin II part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 7.
  - Viola part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 8.
  - Violoncello part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 9.
  - Percussion part. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound., 10.
  - Piano part. Autograph manuscript holograph. Draft/sketches for Capriccio movement., 11.
  - Full score. Autograph manuscript holograph. Pages 139–74., 1. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil notations., 2.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score.105 pages., 3.
- Blue Air, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  Instrumentation: Violin, Piano.
  Dedication: for Roger Zahab.
  At end: "11/96 MacDowell Colony/Pittsburgh"
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. Spiral-bound. Has recording session timing notes and other notations in pencil, 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections. 20 pages., 2.
- No Time Like the Present, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  Instrumentation: 2 Flutes, 1 Piccolo/Flute 3, 2 Oboes, 1 English Horn, 2 Clarinets in B-flat, 1 Bass Clarinet/Clarinet 3, 3 Bassoons, 4 Horns in F, 3 Trumpets in C, 3 Trombones, 1 Tuba, Timpani, 3 Percussion, Harp, Piano, Strings.
  Dedication: Mariss Jansons and the Pittsburgh Symphony
  At end: MacDowell Colony August 1996
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 44 pages, double-sided. Note on cover sheet: "Consoli's Suggestions." Notations in pen., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. 44 pages, double-sided. With copy of handwritten errata sheet., 2.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 44 pages, single-sided., 3.
  - Full score. Computer generated score. 44 pages, double-sided., 4.
  - Full score.Computer generated score. 35 pages (11 x 17)., 5.
  - Individual parts for Flute 1, Flute 2, Flute 3/Piccolo, Oboe 1, Oboe 2, English Horn, Clarinet 1, Clarinet 2, Clarinet 3/Bass Clarinet, Bassoon 1, Bassoon 2, Bassoon 3/Contra Bassoon, Horn 1, 2, 3 and 4, Trumpet 1, 2 and 3, Trombone 1, 2, and 3, Tuba, Timpani, Percussion, Harp, Piano, Violin I and II, Viola, Violoncello and Contrabass. Computer-generated score. 1 copy of each part., 1. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Individual parts for Violin I, Violin II, Viola, Violoncello and Contrabass. Computer-generated holograph (11 x 14). 1 copy of each part., 2.
  - Full score. Copy of computer-generated draft with handwritten additions (11X17). 3 copies., 3.
  - Full score. Copy of computer-generated draft with handwritten additions (11X17). 3 copies., 4.
  - Handwritten notes. 1 page. In envelope., 1. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Contract and correspondence with Pittsburgh Symphony re commission. 3 pages. In envelope., 2.
  - Full score. Copy of computer-generated score. In envelope. 4 copies., 3.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pen and pencil corrections. 146 pages., 4.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 44 pages. 2 copies., 5.
  - Full score. Computer-generated holograph. 35 pages (8 ½ x 14). Handwritten notation on cover page: "old.", 6.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 28 leaves (14 blank)., 7.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score (11X17). Spiral bound., 1. (Box 29, Folder 2)
- Songs of Connection, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  Instrumentation: Soprano, Flute, Harp.
  Dedication: for Christine Schadeberg.
  At end: "MacDowell Colony 7/96"
  Notes: Three movements: I. The Players ask for a Blessing on the Psalteries and on Themselves (based on text by W.B. Yeats); II. Upon Julia's Voice (based on text by Robert Herrick); III. Measuring the World (based on text by Erica Funkhouser).
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts. Partial copies. 21 pages., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 27 pages., 2.
  - Individual parts for flute and harp. Computer generated score., 3.
  - Erica Funkhouser poem with correspondence from poet. 2 pages., 4.
  - Lyrics. 2 pages., 5.
  - Notes in pencil. 1 page., 6.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections. 11 pages., 7.
  - Full score. Computer-generated holograph. Pencil corrections. 7 pages., 8.
  - Full score. Computer generated holograph. Pencil corrections. 9 pages., 9.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 25 leaves (9 blank)., 10.
- Time Will Tell, 1996 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  Instrumentation: Flute/Piccolo, Clarinet in A/Bass Clarinet, Violin, Viola, Piano.
  Dedication: for Lou Karchin and the Washington Square Contemporary Music Ensemble
  - Individual Flute/Piccolo part. Spiral bound. 9 pages., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 46 pages. Handwritten note in upper right corner of title page: "older.", 2.
  - Full score. Computer-generated and autograph manuscript dated revised pages., 3.
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts., 4.
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts and dated revised pages., 5.
  - Note in pencil. 1 page., 6.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 40 leaves (21 blank)., 7.
- And Life Like Froth Doth Throb, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  Intstrumentation: Viola
  Dedication: for Cynthia Fogg and Tom Flaherty
  At end: "The MacDowell Colony, 5/8/97"
  - Viola score. Computer-generated sketches and draft., 1.
  - Viola score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil notations.7 pages., 2.
  - Viola score. Computer-generated draft. Corrections in pencil., 3.
  - Viola score. Computer-generated score. 2 copies., 4.
- Nocturne, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  Instrumentation: Piano
  At end: "MacDowell Colony 5/19/1997"
  - Piano score. Computer-generated draft & dated revised pages., 1.
  - Piano score. Computer-generated score. 4 pages., 2.
- Sonnets to Orpheus, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  Instrumentation: Soprano, Oboe, two Violins, Viola, Cello, Piano.
  Dedication: for Christine Brandes and J. Karla Lemon in admiration and in friendship
  Commissioned by: Christine Brandes
  At end: "10/5/1997 The MacDowell Colony - Pittsburgh"
  Notes: Based on texts by Rainer Maria Rilke, translated by Stephen Mitchell. Eight movements.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 116 pages., 1.
  - Reduction for Soprano and Piano. Computer-generated score. 2 copies., 2.
  - Copies of "The Sonnets to Orpheus" poems. Includes some pencil notations. 15 pages. Computer printouts of poems. Includes pencil notes. 9 pages. Handwritten pencil notes of lyric ideas., 3.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 79 leaves (30 blank). Computer printed lyric sheets. 3 pages. Interspersed with autograph manuscript pages., 4.
- Fled Is That Music, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  Instrumentation: Flute, Piano.
  Dedication: for Rachel Rudich
  At end: "Virginia Center for the Creative Arts 6/27/98"
  Notes: Two movements: I. Lament; II. Caprice.
  - Piano part. Computer-generated draft with corrections in pencil. 20 pages., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections. Handwritten note in upper left-hand corner of title page: "old draft." 35 pages., 2.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 12 leaves (1 blank), 3.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. Written in pencil on first page: "6/27/98." 35 pages., 4.
  - Flute part. Computer-generated score. 19 pages., 5.
- The Lone Cello, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  Instrumentation: Cello.
  Notes: Three movements: I. Back in the Saddle; II. The Lone Prairie; III. Heading the Philistines Off at the Pass.
  - Cello part. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections and alternate titles. Title on page: "Declaration of Independence." Handwritten notes: "In the Saddle" and "Hot on the Trail." 6 pages., 1.
  - Cello part. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections. Handwritten title: "Declaration of Independence." 8 pages., 2.
  - Cello part. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections. Handwritten title: "Declaration of Independence." 8 pages., 3.
  - Cello part. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections. Handwritten notes: "The Lonely trail" and "The Lone Prairie." 2 pages., 4.
  - Cello part. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections. Handwriten notes: "(Shootout w/the Philistines)" and "Heading of the Philistines at the Pass." 7 pages., 5.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 14 leaves (7 blank)., 6.
- Siren Songs, 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  Instrumentation: Soprano, Flutes 1 and 2, Oboes 1 and 2, Clarinets 1 and 2 in B-flat, Bass Clarinet, Bassoons 1 and 2, Horns 1 and 2, Trumpets 1 and 2 in B-flat, Percussion, Piano, Strings.
  Dedication: "for Janet McAdams;" and "For Furious Band"
  At end:12/5/98 Ragdale Foundation/Claremont CA/Pgh. PA (from published score)
  Notes: Six movements: I. The Lost Mermaid (McAdams); II. The Sirens (Kafka); III. Beauty, That Lying Bitch (McLain); IV. The Song of the Sirens (Homer, translated by Pope); V. Eyewitness Account (Whitbourne); VI. In the Hour Before Dawn (Dante).
  - Autograph manuscript score. Sketches. 32 leaves (11 blank)., 1.
  - Kafka text. 1 page., 2.
  - Printouts of email messages regarding texts and the composition. 5 pages., 3.
  - Soprano and Piano reduction. Computer-generated draft.14 pages. Handwritten title: "Beauty, that lying bitch." With pen and pencil notations., 4.
  - Soprano and Piano reduction. Computer-generated draft.5 pages. Handwritten title: "Beauty, that lying bitch." With pen corrections., 5.
  - Soprano and Piano reduction. Computer-generated draft. No title indicated. 12 pages., 6.
  - Soprano &and Piano reduction. Computer-generated holograph. 5 pages. Handwritten title: "The Lost Mermaid." With pencil corrections., 7.
  - Soprano and piano reduction. Computer-generated draft. No title listed. 2 pages, 8.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 16 leaves (7 blank)., 9.
  - Poems/lyrics. 12 pages (4 computer, 7 copies from book, 1 written in pen)., 10.
  - Soprano and Piano reduction. Computer-generated draft. Pencil notations. 17 pages., 11.
  - Poems/lyrics. 36 pages (11 computer generated with pencil notes, 24 copies from books, and 1 in pencil)., 12.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 134 pages., 1. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Soprano and Piano reduction. Computer-generated score. 50 pages. 3 copies., 2.
  - Full score. Composer's computer generated draft with corrections. Instrumentation for this version: Soprano, Flute/Piccolo, B-flat Clarinet, Violin, Cello, Piano. 40 pages. 2 copies., 3.
  - Full score. Computer-generated holograph. 133 pages., 4.
  - Soprano and Piano reduction. Computer-generated draft. Titles of movements written in pencil, some pencil corrections., 5.
  - Flute 1 part. Computer-generated score. 9 pages., 1. (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Flute 2 part. Computer-generated score. 7 pages., 2.
  - Oboe 1 part. Computer-generated score. 7 pages., 3.
  - Oboe 2 part. Computer-generated score. 6 pages., 4.
  - B-flat Clarinet 1 part. Computer-generated score. 10 pages., 5.
  - B-flat Clarinet 2 part. Computer-generated score. 7 pages., 6.
  - Bass Clarinet part. Computer-generated score. 6 pages., 7.
  - Basson 1 part. Computer-generated score. 9 pages., 8.
  - Bassoon 2 part. Computer-generated score. 6 pages., 9.
  - Horn 1 part. Computer-generated score. 7 pages., 10.
  - Horn 2 part. Computer-generated score. 6 pages., 11.
  - Trumpet 1 part. Computer-generated score. 4 pages., 12.
  - Trumpet 2 part. Computer-generated score. 4 pages., 13.
  - Percussion 1 part. Computer-generated score. 9 pages., 14.
  - Percussion 2 part. Computer-generated score. 9 pages., 15.
  - Piano part. Computer-generated score. 16 pages., 16.
  - Violin 1 part. Computer-generated score. 15 pages., 17.
  - Violin 2 part. Computer-generated score. 12 pages., 18.
  - Viola part. Computer-generated score. 11 pages., 19.
  - Cello part. Computer-generated score. 11 pages., 20.
  - Contrabass part. Computer-generated score. 4 pages., 21.
- Dance of the Honey Monkey, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Computer generated draft. Pencil corrections. 10 pages., 1.
  - Computer generated draft. Pencil corrections. 4 pages., 2.
  - Computer generated draft. Pencil corrections. 1 page., 3.
  - Computer generated draft. Pencil corrections. 5 pages., 4.
  - Computer generated draft. Pencil corrections. 5 pages., 5.
  - Computer generated draft. Pencil corrections. 3 pages., 6.
  - Computer generated draft. Pencil corrections. 1 page., 7.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 20 leaves (7 blank)., 8.
- Rough Winds do Shake the Darling Bud, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  Instruments: Alto Sax, Tenor Sax and Baritone Sax.
  At end: "The MacDowell Colony - Pittsburgh, PA 11/22"
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 36 leaves (18 blank)., 1.
  - Computer generated draft. 7 pages., 2.
  - Computer generated draft. 1 page., 3.
  - Computer generated draft. 8 pages., 4.
  - Computer generated draft. 7 pages., 5.
  - Computer generated draft. 30 pages., 6.
  - Computer generated draft. 12 pages, 7.
- Dead Elf Tugboat, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  Instrumentation: Flute, Keyboard Sampler.
  Commissioned by: Rachel Rudich
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pages 1–9 only, 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pages 1–6 only, 2.
  - Full score. Computer-generated dated revised pages., 3.
  - Flute part. Computer-generated score., 4.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score., 5.
- The Shocked Music of Pearls, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  Instrumentation: 2 Violins, Viola, Cello, Contrabass.
  Dedication: some copies state "for Emily Onderdonk;" others state "for Emily Onderdonk and ELIXIR"
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 22 pages., 1.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 28 leaves (15 blank). There is no title, but the word "Elixir," which is part of the dedication, appears at the top of one page., 2.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 28 leaves (15 blank). There is no title, but the word "Elixir," which is part of the dedication, appears at the top of one page., 3.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pen and pencil corrections. 11 pages., 4.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil corrections. 13 pages., 5.
- Time, a Maniac, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  Instrumentation: [Wind ensemble.]
  Commissioned by: [Washington & Jefferson College, Washington, PA]
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 12 leaves (8 blank)., 1.
- Repeat Offender, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. 3 pages., 1.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches and drafts. 30 leaves., 2.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches., 3.
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts., 4.
- Three Ways to Relieve Tension, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  Dedication: for Andrew Imbrie, in his 80th year
  Commissioned by: Meet-the-Composer U.S.A. for David Holzman
  At end: "5/18/01 Psh.PA/Hoboken, NJ
  Notes: Three movements: I. Song of the Mackerel; II. Well I Wish I Was a Catfish; III. Catch and Release.
  - Piano score. Computer-generated draft of movement II. Handwritten note on one page: "Catfish.", 1.
  - Piano score. Computer-generated score.. 20 pages, including title page and performance notes., 2.
  - Piano score. Computer-generated draft. With title caption. Pencil notations. Pages 5, 10, and 11 are missing.17 pages., 3.
  - Piano score. Computer-generated draft. With title caption. Pencil notations. Pages 5, 10, and 11 are missing.17 pages., 4.
- Eight-Point Turn, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  Instrumentation: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, Viola, Contrabass, Percussion, Piano.
  Dedication: for Henry Onderdonk
  Commissioned by: "Eight-Point Turn was commissioned for the Relâche Ensemble with the generous support of the
  National endowment for the Arts and the Philadelphia Music Project, funded by The Pew Charitable Trusts, administered by Settlement Music School.
  At end: "6/29/01 Montana Artists Refuge"
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil notations. 27 pages, including title page and performance notes., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil notations. Pages 1-13 only., 2.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil notations. Pages 1-14 only., 3.
- Fierce Lament, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  Instrumentation: Flute, Oboe, B-flat Clarinet, Bassoon, French Horn, Trumpet, Tenor Trombone, Tuba, Timpani, Vibraphone, Piano, Violin, Viola, Violoncello, Contrabass.
  Dedication: in memoriam 9/11/01
  At end: "Jersey City 3/7/02"
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Pencil notations. 29 pages., 1.
  - Reduced score for Piano, Violin I & II. Computer-generated draft. Alternate title: "Short Lament," dated 2/10. Pages 1-4 only., 2.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Title cut off first page. Pages 1-4, 9-15, and 17., 3.
- Down the Stream, Merrily, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  Instrumentation: 2 Marimbas.
  Dedication: for Stephen Paysen and Dominic Donato
  At end: "July 2002 Montana Artists Refuge Basin MT"
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts., 1.
- Teeth of the Sea, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  Instrumentation: Percussion.
  Dedication: for Michael Lipsey
  Commissioned by: Michael Lipsey
  At end: "August 23, 2003 Montana Artists Refuge"
  - Individual parts labeled "Percussion" and "Drums." Computer-generated draft with corrections in pencil. Includes two pages of handwritten performance notes, 1.
  - Congas part. Computer-generated score. Pencil notations. 3 pages., 2.
  - Congas part. Computer-generated score. 2 copies., 3.
- Berceuse, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  Notes: Subtitle is "The Song of the Three-Headed Siren."
  - Full score. Computer-generated dated revised pages., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 4 pages., 2.
- Echo's Brief Lament, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  Dedication: for Miranda Jacoby
  Commissioned by: [Thalia Myers for Spectrum 4]
  Note: [Published by the Associated board for the Royal School of Music (UK)]
  - Piano score. Computer-generated drafts., 1.
- Preamble & Dreamsong from the 4-5 a.m. REM Stage, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  Instrumentation: Alto Flute [or viola], Piano
  Commissioned by: [the Philadelphia Music Project and NEA for Relâche]
  Note: Alternate title on some copies is "Palaver & Dreamsong"
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts, 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 7 pages., 2.
  - Alto flute part. Computer-generated score. 2 pages., 3.
- Bobby Moon, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  Instrumentation: Not designated. Described by composer as "Electroacoustic Music."
  Note: Created for Carolyn Speranza as music for a documentary video by Speranza.. Funded by the Heinz Foundation. Documentary presented March 2, 2003.
  - Recording notes and email correspondence with Speranza., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts., 2.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches., 3.
- Tri-Stan, 2003 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  Instrumentation: Voice [Mezzo-Soprano], Piano. Also a score included for Flute, Oboe, Clarinet in B-flat, Trumpet in C, Horn in F, Violin, Viola, Cello, Percussion, Voice, Piano.
  Commissioned by: [Mary Nessinger].
  At end: "July 19, 2003 / Montana Artists Refuge, Basin, MT"
  Notes: [Based on text by David Foster Wallace; video by Suzie Silver].
  - Notes and Wallace text., 1.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 18 leaves., 2.
  - Voice and Piano reduction. Computer-generated and autograph manuscript drafts, assorted undated pages., 3.
  - Voice, Piano, and Percussion reduction. Computer-generated draft. Pencil notations. 92 pages, missing page 30., 4.
  - Piano, Voice and Percussion reduction. Computer-generated score. Spiral bound. 89 pages. Computer-generated note in upper-left corner of title page: "unrevised piano vocal score.", 5.
  - Full score, chamber orchestra version. Computer-generated draft. Pen notations. 374 pages. In box labeled "full score 11/03, draft, w/corrections.", 1.
- The Sun Beats the Mountain Like a Drum, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  Instrumentation: Pipa and Electroacoustic Sound
  Dedication: for Wu Man
  Commissioned by: Fromm Foundation for Wu Man
  At end: "7/31/2004 Montana Artists Refuge"
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 22 pages, including title page and performance notes., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 23 pages., 2.
  - Full score. Computer-generated draft. Alternate title handwritten on first page: "Skin of the Mountains." 23 pages., 3.
- Legend of the Sad Triad, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  Dedication: for Jeanne Golan
  At end: "6/28/2004 Montana Artists Refuge, Basin, MT"
  - Piano score. Computer-generated score. 19 pages, including title page and performance notes., 1.
  - Piano score. Computer-generated score. Pencil notations. 19 pages, including title page and performance notes., 2.
- Dr. Devilboy's Drum Machine, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  Instrumentation: Congas, Drum Set, Piano.
  Dedication: for Tom Flaherty
  - Full score. Computer-generated score. 19 pages., 1.
- A Fever of Ice / Melancholia, Baby / Ice Burned and Was But The More Ice, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  Note: Various drafts have different titles listed.
  - Piano score. Computer-generated drafts and dated revised pages., 1.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches., 2.
- Strange Exclaiming Music, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  Commissioned by: [Curtis Macomber].
  Note: Three movements: I. Rhyme Does Not Pay; II. Aria; III. Sorbet of Regret.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts and dated page revisions., 2.
- O the Flesh is Hot but the Heart is Cold, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  Instrumentation: Soprano, Alto, Tenor, Bass.
  Commission: Commissioned by Volti.
  Note: Based on text by Matthea Harvey.
  - Autograph manuscript sketches. 4 leaves., 1.
  - Full score. Computer-generated drafts and dated revised pages., 2.
  - Copy of text., 3.
  - Copy of email correspondence with notes about the piece., 4.
- She Goes Her Spacious Way, 2005 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  Commission: [commissioned by Mary Nessinger and Jeanne Golan]